<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Enumeration on Adamino CTF Writeups</title><link>https://ctf.adamino.dk/categories/enumeration/</link><description>Recent content in Enumeration on Adamino CTF Writeups</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Adamino 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:12:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ctf.adamino.dk/categories/enumeration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Netcat</title><link>https://ctf.adamino.dk/tools/enumeration/nc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:12:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ctf.adamino.dk/tools/enumeration/nc/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="unleashing-netcats-potential-in-capture-the-flag-ctf-challenges">Unleashing Netcat&amp;rsquo;s Potential in Capture The Flag (CTF) Challenges&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Netcat, often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Swiss army knife&amp;rdquo; of networking, is a versatile utility that reads and writes data across network connections using the TCP/IP protocol. Its flexibility and ease of use make it an invaluable tool in Capture The Flag (CTF) challenges, where participants seek to exploit vulnerabilities and capture hidden flags. Let&amp;rsquo;s delve into the myriad ways Netcat can be utilized in CTF scenarios.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nmap</title><link>https://ctf.adamino.dk/tools/enumeration/nmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 23:56:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ctf.adamino.dk/tools/enumeration/nmap/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mastering-nmap-a-comprehensive-guide-to-network-exploration-and-security-auditing">Mastering Nmap: A Comprehensive Guide to Network Exploration and Security Auditing&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Nmap, short for Network Mapper, is an indispensable tool in the arsenal of every network administrator, cybersecurity professional, and ethical hacker. This open-source utility is designed for network exploration and security auditing. It uses raw IP packets to determine available hosts on a network, the services those hosts are offering, the operating systems they are running, and a plethora of other characteristics. This guide will walk you through the essentials of Nmap, covering its installation, basic and advanced usage, and tips for effective network management and security auditing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>